# TIANYU WANG

 $(+86)18258882697 \diamond wtyatzoo@zju.edu.cn \\ https://wtyatzoo.github.io/ <math display="inline">\diamond https://github.com/WTYatzoo/$ 

## **BIOGRAPHY**

Now I am a senior R&D engineer at Faceunity Technology at Hangzhou and a visiting researcher at State Key Lab of CAD&CG, Zhejiang University, hosted by Prof. Kun Zhou. Before that, I got my M.Eng. degree from the same university advised by Prof. Jin Huang and my B.Eng. degree from Sichuan University. My current research interest includes (a). physically based differentiable simulation, (b). inverse problems in fabrication and design, (c). human digitization.

#### **EDUCATION**

Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China M.Eng. in Computer Science Sichuan University, Chengdu, China B.Eng. in Computer Science

Sept. 2016 - Mar. 2020 Advisor: Prof. Jin Huang Sept. 2012 - Jun. 2016

### **PUBLICATION**

**Tianyu Wang**, Dongping Li, Xiaowei Liu, Jiong Chen, Huamin Wang, Kun Zhou A Two-Way Interior Point Method for Collision Handling in Deformable Body Simulation to be submitted to  $SIGGRAPH\ 2022$ 

## Tianyu Wang

Super-resolution of shallow water equation simulation based on GAN Master Thesis at Zhejiang University 2020

Jiong Chen, Hujun Bao, **Tianyu Wang**, Mathieu Desbrun, Jin Huang Numerical Coarsening using Discontinuous Shape Functions *ACM Transaction Graphics* 37(4)(SIGGRAPH 2018), Vancouver, Canada, 2018

## INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Senior R&D Engineer, Faceunity Technology Co. Ltd, Hangzhou

May 2020 - Now

· Co-developed a GPU-based cloth simulation CAD software as the core engineer

R&D Intern, Xmov Technology Co. Ltd, Shanghai

Sept. 2019 - Jan. 2020

Mentor: Prof. Jinxiang Chai

- · Developed an open-sourced single view based hair modeling system
- · Developed static hair/cloth retargeting algorithms for artists

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Visiting Researcher, State Key Lab of CAD&CG, ZJU Host: Prof. Kun Zhou

Oct. 2021 - Now

· Lead research on collision handling of deformable body (to be submitted to SIGGRAPH 2022)

Research Assistant, State Key Lab of CAD&CG, ZJU Advisor: Prof. Jin Huang

Sept. 2016 - Mar. 2020

- · Research on super-resolution of shallow water equation simulation (Master Thesis 2020)
- Participated in research on numerical coarsening of FEM based simulation (SIGGRAPH 2018)

#### SELECTED CHRONOLOGICAL R&D EXPERIENCE DETAILS

R&D on GPU-based deformable body simulation and collision handling, 2020 - Now commercial use

## Developed an open-sourced single view based hair modeling system, 2019

Development of using a single image as input to reconstruct the 3D hair model to accelerate the process of hair asset production for artists. I surveyed 18 representative related papers from 2012 to 2019 and understood its evolution clearly. According to four aspects: (a). robustness of the algorithm, (b). whether the input of algorithm matches the input from the current available hardware, (c). whether the output of algorithm can be used for simulation, (d). whether the data flow of the algorithm can be refined by artists flexibly, I implemented, modified and combined existed algorithms from scratch to make a tool for artists. See the *hair report* for more implementation details. Find the source code *here*.

## Developed static hair/cloth retargeting algorithms for artists, 2019

Development of retargeting a hair/cloth model from one suited character to another different character. I used less than a day to design and implement the algorithm for hair retargeting based on ARAP deformation and the artists gave a positive feedback to my timely help. Find the source code *here*. After surveying cloth retargeting related papers, I gave out a suitable solution to the artists. See the *retargeting report* for details.

# Research on super-resolution of shallow water equation simulation, 2018 - 2019

My master thesis proposed to achieve the SWE data's super-resolution using generative adversarial network. After considering the temporal smoothness constraint, rotation equivalence requirement, the possible negative value, this thesis proposed some insightful modifications to the state of the art framework and obtained verified better results. See the *SWE report* for details.

Participated in research on numerical coarsening of FEM based simulation, 2017 - 2018 Research on numerical coarsening to accelerate the FEM based solid simulation with heterogeneous materials and non-linear constitutive laws on coarse grid. See our *paper* on SIGGRAPH 2018 for more details. I implemented a FEM based solid simulation framework and did the major two papers' comparison experiments quickly and independently from scratch.

# HONORS AND AWARDS

Graduate of Merit/Triple A graduate, Zhejiang University, 2018 Award of Honor for Graduate, Zhejiang University, 2018 Wen Chixiang Scholarship, Zhejiang University, 2018 Silver Medal, ACM-ICPC China Provincial Programming Contest, Chengdu Site, 2013 and 2014 2nd University Scholarship, Sichuan University, 2013

## **SKILLS**

**English** TOEFL score: 102 (R:29 L:24 S:21 W:28)

Programming Languages C, C++, Python

Main Toolkit CUDA, Eigen, NumPy, Tensorflow, PyQt, OpenGL, LATEX, Git

Software ParaView, MeshLab, Maya, Blender, Origin, Office